Isaac Shepard

SOFTWARE ENGINEER * MATHEMATICS - COMPUTER SCIENCE MAJOR * UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO

📞 (858)-357-6167 | 🗷 ishepard@ucsd.edu | 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/isaacshepard77/ | 🎵 https://github.com/shepardi

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in designing and building responsive web applications using Javascript and Python frameworks with GIT version control.

- * Familiar with Shell Scripting, TCP/IP.
- Familiar with using AWS cloud storage and CI/CD pipelines.
- Solid foundation in computer science topics: Object Oriented Programming, data structures and algorithms.

Skills

Programming C/C++ · Python · NodeJS

Full-Stack HTML / CSS / Javascript · Express · React · MongoDB · Django · PostgreSQL

Experience

Junior Full Stack Developer

April, 2020 - August, 2020

General Assembly - | MongoDB · ReactJS · NodeJS · Express

Built web applications using Javascript and Python with MVC Frameworks

- Refactored raw queries from SQL into Django ORM.
- > Built responsive features allowing better user experience for mobile devices
- > Refactored web applications into ReactJS allowing for faster rendering and future feature implementations

Unity VR Game Developer

January, 2017 - March, 2018

Triton XR - | C#' Unity3D ' Google Daydream

Leveraged the Unity3D system, C# scripting, and GoogleVR to build a mobile virtual reality game Lucid Dreaming.

- Developed game design and levels using the Unity game engine built for the Google DayDream headset and controllers.
- Followed an Agile workflow and GIT version control (Github) for more efficient productivity on individual features.
- > Built character and environment animations for better user experience using C# scripting.

Game Project Page: www.phillipaisling.com/blog-post/lucid-dream-training-in-a-virtual-reality-game/

Technical Projects _____

Albion Online Hub

July, 2020 - Now

WEB APPLICATION - | MongoDB · ReactJS · NodeJS · Express |

[Albion Online Hub is a web application made for the MMORPG game Albion Online. Uses the game's API to get a JSON payload for app features.]

Leveraged MERN web stack and github workflow to build a responsive web application following the MVC design pattern

- > Incorporated RESTful routing allowing cleaner data manipulation for the group organize feature.
- > Integrated Albion Online's game API inorder to synchronize data for the gold-market graph feature.
- > Handled user authentication authorization using MongoDB and Express framework to ensure a proper login feature.
- > Utilized a CI workflow and unit testing to allow easier integration of a new feature.
- > Refactored main project branch into a React application and incorporated TDD with Jest/Enzyme testing.

Wayfarer July, 2020 - July, 2020

WEB APPLICATION - | Python · Django · PostgreSQL · Bootstrap |

[Wayfarer is a Python based web application that acts as a hub for world travelers to post interesting landmarks that are worth visiting.]

Leveraged Python, Django, and PostgreSQL to build a Travel/Blog web application.

- ➤ Used Django RESTful framework to handle the web applications routes.
- > Collaborated with a team following an agile workflow while using Github for version control.
- Made use of Django's OAuth toolkit to handle user authentication and authorization for account login features.
- > Incorporated responsive design on landmark posting feature to allow a smooth user experience

Shots January, 2016 - March, 2017

ANDROID APPLICATION - | Java · Firebase · |

[Shots is an Android Mobile Application that allows media "stories" to be shared among friends that you where with the night before.]

Leveraged Java, Android Studio, Google Firebase to build a mobile application.

- > Developed map tracking feature that tracks other users within a group.
- > Collaborated with a team of eight peers to document and build the android application.
- > Configured local storage and cloud storage using Firebase (non-relational database.
- > Pushed out group messaging features, allowing other users to add and create a chat group and share media files.
- Used TDD to document and push out quality code.

Education

University of California, San Diego - Mathematics/Computer Science General Assembly - Software Engineering September, 2016 - March, 2020 June, 2020 - August, 2020